...Such a pleasure to come back to you all.
...能再次見到你們所有人真是非常愉快
I was looking forward to it.
我一直期待這一刻
I received all your letters and greeting and all that you told.
我收到你們的信、問候以及你們所訴說的一切
It was so loving and so encouraging
這是充滿愛 也非常令人振奮 ..
to know about your progress here
來瞭解你們的進展
and when I was really working very, very, very, very hard,
當我工作非常、非常、非常、非常努力的時候
I used to think of you
我總會想起你們
and I would
然後我就會
put this idea into my mind
把這個想法放進我的內裡
that a day will come
那一天將會來到
when the prophecy of William Blake must come true.
威廉·布萊克的預言必定會實現
I went to Australia
我去了澳洲
and I was amazed the way miracles took place
我對在那個國家奇蹟發生的方式
in that country.
感到驚嘆
It is said that in the Puranas
據說在《往世書》中記載
there was a saint called Thrissanku,
曾有位叫特里桑庫的聖人
who committed some mistake, little mistake
犯了一些小錯誤
and he was sent
因此他被放逐
as the Southern Cross hanging in the air
成為懸掛在空中的南十字星
and was told that you must create your own heaven.
並被告知必須創造自己的天堂
And really Australia is heaven, no doubt, but itís Mooladhara.
澳洲確實是天堂，毫無疑問，它是根輪所在
It is Mooladhara.
它就是根輪
The people are
那裡的人們
of course getting all the ideas, over read, as we are here.
當然也接收了所有這些觀念，過度解讀，就像我們在這裡一樣
We have accepted all these also wrong ideas quite a lot.
我們也接受了很多這些錯誤的觀念
But somehow I feel it still in the heart of heart,
但不知為何，我仍然在內心深處感覺到
they feel that this may not be correct way of life
他們感受到這可能不是正確的生活方式
and they still feel that some off the things we do is not
而且他們仍然覺得我們做的某些事情並不是
absolutely perfect
絕對完美的
or is not the thing that we really [unclear].
或者不是我們真正要的東西
There are all sorts of gurus in Australia,
澳洲有各式各樣的導師
all sorts of people who are there.
各式各樣的人都在那裡
But basically
但基本上
they do not accept now people
他們現在不接受
who
那些
who come there and preach absurd things
去那裡傳播荒謬言論的人
without any [unclear] to the ancient scriptures and things.
任何沒有與古代經典相關的事物
So they are traditional people in a way,
所以從某種程度上來說，他們是傳統的人
as far as their religious ideas are concerned.
就他們的宗教觀念而言
But they are
但他們是
very, very open-minded,
非常、非常開明
for example, the first miracle that took place
例如，第一個發生的奇蹟
was that there was a lady who was an actress,
是有一位女士，她是演員
who was very sick.
當時病得很重
She got her paralysis attack or some sort of thing like that
她得了癱瘓之類的病
and the doctor said that she will not be cured.
醫生說她無法治癒
She will die maybe next day
她可能隔天就會死
and there is no possibility of her getting cured.
而且沒有康復的可能性
So the friend of hers, who is a very big journalist,
所以她一位身為知名記者的朋友
he came to a homeopath who is
去找了一位
a Sahaj yogi,
從事順勢療法醫師的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
and asked if she could help with homeopathy.
詢問是否能以順勢療法幫助她
So she said I canít help you with homeopathy,
她說我無法用順勢療法幫你
only thing I have got is - ëphotographí, which you can take it
我唯一有的是這張「照片」，你可以拿去
and put it under her pillow and maybe this might work.
放在她枕頭下，或許會有效
So he took the photograph because she was a [unclear],
於是他拿了照片，因為她已經..
there was nothing to be questioned,
沒什麼好質疑的
and put it under her pillow and next day she opened her eyes.
並將它放在枕頭下，隔天她就睜開了眼睛
And they couldnít believe it.
而他們簡直不敢相信
And as usual doctors said, "oh must be this - must be that, you see,
一如往常地，醫生們說：「噢，一定是這樣——一定是那樣，你看
sure she should not, she should not in any case survive,
她絕對不該，無論如何都不該存活下來
because in any case her brain is damaged, no doubt,
因為無論如何她的腦部都已經受損，毫無疑問
we have seen it that her brain is damaged."
我們都親眼見證她腦部確實受損了。」
But next day she started talking.
但隔天她竟然開始說話了
They couldnít believe it
他們簡直不敢相信
that she is talking, that means that her brain alright.
她竟然能開口說話，這表示她的腦部很正常
She improved gradually.
她逐漸好轉起來
But all this click
但這一切都來得如此突然
a different atmosphere,
截然不同的氛圍
a very different atmosphere for Sahaja Yoga,
霎哈嘉瑜伽中一種非常特殊的氛圍
because the one, the friend who was her friend,
因為那位曾是她摯友的人
the one who was very much interested in her heal,
那位對她療癒過程極度關切的人
was a man who is very highly placed in journalism,
是一位在新聞界地位非常高的人
though he is not a Sahaja Yogi or anything but he sent
雖然他並不是霎哈嘉瑜伽士或其他什麼身份，但他派了
a journalist to me,
一位記者來找我
to our program, he and his wife,
他和他的妻子是澳洲記者協會的主席
who is the president of journalist association in Australia,
來參加我們的活動
got realisation.
因此得到自覺
And that really clicked the whole thing.
這真的讓整件事豁然開朗
So these medias can be also used
所以我們這些可以用媒體
and ones they are used you can do a lot of things.
當它們被運作時，你可以做很多事情
But at the helm of affairs we should have people
在掌管事務的崗位上，我們應該要有這樣的人
who are
他們是
not arrogant, are mild.
不傲慢、溫和的
You can say all people
你可以說所有人
who are humble,
那些謙遜的人
humble enough to understand Sahaja Yoga.
謙遜到足以理解霎哈嘉瑜伽的人
Of cause as usual there were some encounters.
當然，一如既往地遇到了一些狀況
One of them was ëtwice borní had come.
其中有一位是「重生者」來了
So they came to fight with me, twice born.
所以他們來與我對抗，「重生者」
And this is actually...
這實際上是...
Twice born, this has come from America.
「重生者」，這是從美國來的
When I went to America last time,
當我上次去美國的時候
they had told me that I must get all my lectures registered
他們告訴我必須將所有的講座登記註冊
and all that kind of a copyright I must keep.
並且要保留所有這類的版權
I said to her, ëwhy should I keep it like that?í
我對她說：「為什麼我要這樣做？」
They said, ëno, no, no, then they will use your lecturesí.
他們說：「不行、不行、不行，這樣他們會亂用你的演講。」
I said, ëlet them use it, after all, realisation I have to give in any case.
我說：「讓他們用吧，畢竟總歸我是要給自覺的。」
They canít give realisation.
那些人是無法給自覺的
So when I said there that ëyou have to be born again,
所以當我說「你們必須重生」時
you are to be twice born, they started an organisation called ëtwice borní.
你將獲得第二次誕生，這些人成立了一個名為「二次誕生」的組織
There are so many, like ëtrue vibrationsí
還有許多類似「真實能量」這樣的組織
all sorts of organisations have started, in America on those lines.
各種類型的組織在美國如雨後春筍般成立，沿著這些路線發展
So this twice born came to fight with me,
於是這個「二次誕生」組織跑來與我對抗
saying that, what is your authority? I said, ëwhat is your authority?í
他們說：「你有甚麼權威？」我說：「那你的權威又是什麼？」
They: ëMy authority is bibleí.
他們回答：「我的權威是聖經。」
I said, ëalright, what is authority of bible?
我說：「好吧，那聖經的權威是什麼？」
They: authority of bible is Christ. I said, ëChrist never wrote bibleí.
他們說：「聖經的權威是基督。」我說：「基督從來沒有寫過聖經。」
He never wrote it, He had nothing to do with bible.
祂從未撰寫過，與聖經毫無關聯
He never wrote it.
祂根本沒有寫過
So they never knew how to answer me...
所以他們不知如何回答我...
They said, ëstill you must have an authority.
他們說：「即便如此，你仍必須有個權威。」
I have, I will prove my authority. First of all you tell me,
我有，我將證明我的權威。首先你告訴我
your authority to ask these questions.
你質問這些的權柄
They carried bible in their hand, you know...
他們手裡拿著聖經，你知道...
He said here is written - I am the Alpha and omega.
他說這裡寫著——我是阿爾法也是歐米茄
I said, He is, but who is goint to accept it.
我說過，祂是存在的，但誰會接受呢？
You believe in Christianity, alright, because you were born in it.
你信仰基督教，好吧，因為你生來就是基督徒
If you were born a Hindu, you would have been Hindu,
如果你生在印度教家庭，你就會成為印度教徒
because you are a type who would belong to something somehow.
因為你們是那種無論如何都要有所歸屬的人
I can prove it, that He was the omega and He was the alpha.
我說，基督既是阿爾法也是歐米茄
Then they started
然後他們開始
attacking this that, somehow everybody
攻擊這個那個，不知怎地後來大家
threw them out and it was over.
把他們都趕出去，事情就這麼結束了
It was very interesting because so many people got realisation
這真的很有趣，因為有這麼多人得到了自覺
and they came to programs that we had, so called seminars.
他們來參加我們舉辦的活動，也就是所謂的研討會
In the open we arranged seminars,
我們在戶外舉辦了研討會
because we had no place to go to with 500 - 600 people.
因為當時找不到能容納 500 到 600 人的場地
So, there is one gentleman who has a big house,
有位先生擁有棟大房子
which has got a big compound. So we invited them, all of them there
房子還附帶寬敞的庭院。所以我們邀請了所有人到那裏
because [unclear]. And the whole [unclear] was there. It was like a
因為..整個..都在場。那場景就像
sermon on the mount, sort of thing. So many of them sitting there
耶穌在山上佈道那樣。很多人坐在那裏
and having their food and they talking and all that.
他們享用食物、聊天，做著這些事情
So many people getting cured,
許多人因此獲得療癒
it was really remarkable the way these people took such interest
這些人展現的熱忱真的非常了不起
and came all the way and from the first time they had their realisation
他們不遠千里而來，第一次就得到了自覺
and every day they came for about seven days,
他們每天都來，持續了大約七天
every day, every evening they all came from all over the place.
每天，每個傍晚，他們從四面八方趕來
We had people from Tasmania who came down
我們有從塔斯馬尼亞來的訪客
and we had people from Melbourne,
也有從墨爾本來的朋友
from New Zealand, from all over, we got people there.
來自紐西蘭、來自世界各地的人都聚集在那裡
They came and stayed in the ashram. Ashram itself is another beautiful place.
他們來到靈舍並住了下來。靈舍本身就是一個非常美麗的地方
Thereís a miraculous story, they say that, one day Meera rang me up
有個神奇的傳說，據說有一天米拉打電話給我
to say that, they have already sold their house, weíve got no place to go to
告訴我說他們已經賣掉了房子，現在無處可去
and we canít find a place to live in,
我們找不到住的地方
because they were expecting some place to come through
因為他們原本期待有地方可以住
but there is no place available.
但現在沒有任何空房
I said alright now donít worry tomorrow you will get the place.
我說好吧別擔心，明天你們就會有地方住了
And she couldnít believe it, how can that be.
而她不敢相信，怎麼可能有這種事
And they had told about two hundred agents,
而且他們已經告訴了大約兩百個仲介
who said that, there is no such place available
那些人說，根本沒有這樣的場地
and we just canít get you a place.
我們就是沒辦法幫你找到場地
And
而
when he, Terence, her husband had gone out
當她的丈夫特倫斯外出時
and he was looking out for things and he came back home very tired
他外出尋找東西，回家時已經非常疲憊
so Meera said that, ìMother has told that tomorrow you going to get it.
米拉說：「母親告訴我，明天你就能找到。」
He said, ëtomorrow?
他說：「明天？」
Can it be possible?í
這可能嗎？
Said now there was a telephone call in the evening
據說昨晚有個電話
from somewhere and she gave him number.
從某處打來，她給了他號碼
So he rang up in the morning to ask that number, what was it?
所以他早上打去詢問那個號碼，是什麼來著？
It was from and agent.
這是來自一位房仲
They said, we have found a place for you.
他們說：「我們已經為您找到一個地方了。」
If you want you can occupy it right now.
如果您願意，現在就可以入住
So the next day they moved into the house.
於是隔天他們就搬進了那棟房子
Actually they did.
實際上他們確實做到了
And it is a beautiful place with fourteen bedrooms
那是個擁有十四間臥室的美麗場所
and a huge big hall. Itís a beautiful place.
還有一個超大的廳堂，真是個漂亮的地方
So thatís how they got it.
所以他們就是這樣得到它的
So many things work out this way.
很多事情就是這樣順利發展的
And they said that not only that we have got the blessing
他們說不僅我們得到了祝福
but so many miraculous material things are happening
還發生了許多物質上的奇蹟在發生
that we are really surprised.
這真的讓我們感到驚喜
But Iíve already told you that it is written that, ëYoga Kshema Vahamyaí
但我已經告訴過你們，經文上寫著：「瑜伽福祉建造者」
- first you must get your yoga and that kshema will come afterwards.
- 首先你必須獲得瑜伽，之後福祉才會到來
The wellbeing comes afterwards.
福祉是隨之而來的
Of course in the discussion
當然在討論中
it turned out to be
結果卻
something much more revealing
提到了更揭示性的主題
when I was talking to people.
當我和他們交談時
So many things which I have not told you people
到目前為止，還有好多事情我還未告訴你們或印度人
or Indians so far, I told them about Christ.
我向他們講到了基督
I hope you have received their tapes.
錫呂瑪塔吉:我希望你們已經收到他們的錄音帶
Not yet, they are sending.
瑜珈士: 還沒收到，他們正在寄送中
Have you heard them?
錫呂瑪塔吉: 你們聽過了嗎？
What is [unclear] saying?
瑜珈士:還沒
I think you are going into thoughtless awareness isnít it.
錫呂瑪塔吉:我想你們正進入無思慮覺知狀態，不是嗎？
There is nothing they distributed to you.
我打擾了你們 ..
The thing I told them about Christ was this
我告訴他們關於基督的事情是這樣的
that everybody did
每個人都做了
something great for our awareness,
對我們覺知很偉大的事,
like Moses, who brought in the idea of dharma.
像摩西,他帶來了正法的概念
He gave us the idea of balance
他給予我們平衡的概念
and we had Ebrahem and all these people.
我們有亞伯拉罕和所有這些靈性導師
But Christ did the greatest thing in a way,
但從某種角度來看，基督做了最偉大的事
because he came in at a point, which is the Agnya chakra
因為他出現在一個關鍵點——額輪
where ego and superego cross each other.
也就是自我與超我相互交會之處
And, what he did, that all these karma theories that was there, so far
而他所做的，就是對抗過去所有的業力
that you had to suffer your karmas, he came to counter act it, by saying
那些你必須承受自身業力的理論觀念，他以行動反抗
that, ëHe died for our sinsí.
「他為我們的罪(救贖)而死」
Means He can suck our karmas.
意味著祂能吸收我們的業力
So this theory of karma is over now because Christ is born.
所以業力的論點現在已經結束了，因為基督已經誕生
If Christ could be awakened in your agnya chakra
如果基督能在你的額輪中被喚醒
then all your karmas, past karmas,
那麼你所有的業力，過去的業力
all your sins, will be sucked by this awakening.
你所有的罪孽，都將被這自覺所吸取
But Christians, those who went to India, were stupid people.
但那些去印度佈教的基督徒，都是愚蠢之人
They wanted to extend their empire there,
他們想在那裡擴張自己的帝國
on their own, not of Christ.
是出於自身意圖，而非基督的旨意
So they never communicate; I donít know if they even saw what it meant
所以他們從未溝通；我甚至不確定他們是否明白那意味著什麼
- ëdying for our sinsí what it had relation with karma theory.
-「為我們的罪而死」這與業力理論之間的關聯
So when they went to India,
所以當他們到了印度
they put Christ in such a funny way,
他們用一種可笑的方式來詮釋基督
that Indians would not accept, would not accept Him.
印度人不會接受，不會接受祂
And because of that, the integration of Christís life,
正因如此，基督的一生
with Indian philosophy could not take place.
無法與印度哲學相融合
On the contrary, they repelled, completely repelled Him.
相反地，他們排斥，完全排斥了祂
And they could not understand Bible. They would not see it.
而他們無法理解聖經。他們視而不見
Thatís how Christ who came on this earth,
所以基督的降臨
for such a great purpose was to suck our karmas,
是為了如此崇高的目的來承擔我們的業力
was completely lost to them.
卻完全被印度人錯失了
And still so many gurus are talking about our karma theory
然而仍有許多導師在談論我們的業力理論
and making full advantage of it.
並且充分利用這一點
They are not aware that Christ came for this thing.
他們並不知道基督就是為此而來
He has already done it for us. Once your agnya
祂已經為我們完成了這件事。一旦你的額輪
is established and you get your Christ awakened within you,
你內在的基督被喚醒並確立起來
all your previous sins are sucked in.
你過往所有的罪業都會被吸納淨化
But the most unfortunate thing is that
但最不幸的是
those who are supposed to be Christian nations
那些理應是基督教國度的國家
have the worst agnyaís.
卻有著最糟糕的額輪
This is the biggest tragedy is
這是最巨大的悲劇
that they have forgotten the ëLordís Prayerí,
他們遺忘了「主禱文」
which is the mantra for our agnya.
就是為了打開我的們額輪
I think forgiving others is a very important thing.
我認為寬恕他人是非常重要的事
We must learn to forgive.
我們必須學會寬恕
All the time we must learn to forgive.
我們時時刻刻都必須學會寬恕
That is the best way we can keep our agnya in control
這是我們維護額輪的最佳方式
and our ego at its proper level.
而我們的自我也會保持在適當的程度
What right have you got to be not forgiving,
你有什麼權利不去寬恕他人
because by not forgiving you are harming yourself.
因為不寬恕其實是在傷害你自己
Thatís why forgiving others is the only way we can really
這就是為什麼寬恕他人是我們真正能夠
control our agnya. Even forgiving ourselves,
控制我們的額輪。甚至原諒自己
we have to forgive ourselves and we have to forgive others.
我們必須原諒自己，也必須原諒他人
Today is a day, when I should be talking about Sahasrara.
今天是個應該談論頂輪的日子
Because tomorrow is the day of Sahasrara
因為明天就是頂輪日
and that is the greatest blessing of Sahaja Yoga after Christís advent.
而這正是霎哈嘉瑜伽在基督降臨後最大的祝福
Even if He had sucked your sins,
因為祂已吸收了你們的罪
you are to be given realisation.
你們將得到自覺
Without realisation
沒有自覺
it has no meaning
這毫無意義
and so this Sahaja Yoga
而這個霎哈嘉瑜伽
which is todays ëMahaYogaí
也就是今天的「偉大瑜伽」
came into being because you all have to be realised.
之所以存在 是因為你們都必須得到自覺
You have to know yourself.
你們必須認識自己
The Self that is the Spirit,
唯有我們內裡靈的覺醒
that is the only way we can know God.
是我們唯一能認識神的方式
There is no other way
除此之外別無他法
that we can know God.
讓我們得以認識神
We have to be our Spirit.
我們必須成為靈
The second thing that we
基督教國家做的第二件事
in all the Christian nations have done is to forget our Spirit.
就是遺忘了我們是靈
It is a double catch. If the ego develops, it covers your heart.
這是一個雙重陷阱。如果自我膨脹，它就會遮蔽你的心
You can even become emotionless.
你甚至可能變得沒有感情的
When it covers your heart,
當它覆蓋你的心時
then your heart becomes like a stone
你的心就會變得像石頭一樣
and the Spirit does not shine.
而靈也不再閃耀
All the time what you have to say,
隨時,你都必須說
that "Iím the Spirit!"
「我是靈！」
All the realised souls have to say: ìIím the Spirit.
所有自覺靈都必須說：「我是靈
Iím not this body, not this mind,
我不是這個身體，不是這個心智
nor this superego, none of these ëuphadisí as the call them,
也不是這個超我制約，不是所謂的「附屬物」
but Iím the Spirit, the pure Spirit I am.î
「我是靈，純粹的靈」
If you could recognise that part in you, that you are the Spirit,
如果你能認出自己內在的這個部分，也就是你是靈
your realisation will be fully established.
那麼你的自覺將完全確立
As long as you are identified with other things,
只要你仍與其他事物認同
this cannot be established.
這就無法確立
So first and foremost thing you have to recognise
所以首要之務你必須認知到
that you are the Spirit.
你就是靈
You are not the thoughts which are overcrowding you.
你不是那些讓你腦袋擁擠的思緒
You are not
你不是
the fears with which you suffer,
那些讓你受苦的恐懼
you are not the ambitions with which you run,
也不是那些驅使你奔波的野心
but you are that pure Spirit,
但你正是那純淨的靈
which never changes, which is eternal,
永不改變、永恆不滅的那個本質
which is blissful,
充滿至樂的狀態
which is Sat-Chit-Anand.
也就是「真知喜樂」的本體
We all Sahaja Yogis have to know, that we are the Spirit.
我們所有霎哈嘉瑜伽士都必須明白，我們就是靈
This is the mantra that one has to recite for heart catch.
這是清理心輪阻塞必要的口訣
If your heart is not clean,
如果你的心不純淨
you can never get realisation.
就永遠無法獲得自覺
Anybody who comes with funny ideas about Me you have seen,
任何對我有奇怪想法的人，你們都見過了
he never gets realisation.
他們永遠無法得到自覺
You have to have clean heart.
你必須保持純淨的心
You have to cleanse your heart, thatís why I sometimes say
你需要淨化自己的心，這就是為什麼我有時候會說
that you have to put your guru into your heart, who will clean your heart.
你必須將你的導師放在心中，祂會潔淨你的心
Just to clean your heart,
只是為了潔淨你的心
as you employ a maid in the house,
就像你在家中僱用一位女傭
to clean your heart you can employ your mother for that purpose.
為了潔淨你的心，你可以為此目的僱用你的靈性母親
Cleansing is my job, morning till evening Iím cleansing.
淨化是我的工作，從早到晚我都在淨化
Thatís my name means also.
這也是我的名字
But cleansing is such a big thing, such a big thing
但淨化是如此重要的事，如此重要的事
that, that brings forth everything else with it.
那將帶動其他一切隨之而來
If there is dust on the diamond,
如果鑽石上有灰塵
on any diamond which will be very expensive, you cannot see it!
在任何非常昂貴的鑽石上，你看不到！
In the same way if your Spirit is clouded
同樣地，如果你的靈被蒙蔽
with doubts and fears,
充滿疑慮與恐懼
cunningness,
狡猾算計
then your Spirit cannot shine.
那麼你的靈就無法發光
Now, it is such a vicious circle
現在，這簡直就是個惡性循環
that it is not easy to break.
這並不容易打破
Even there your mind can cheat you.
即使在那裡，你的頭腦也可能欺騙你
For Sahaja Yogi it is very easy, is to sit before My photograph,
對於霎哈嘉瑜伽士來說，這非常容易，就是坐在我的照片前
put your left hand here and one on your heart and say: Iím the Spirit.
將你的左手放在這裡，一隻手放在你的心上，然後說：我是靈
Mother, Iím the Spirit.
母親，我是靈
Can you try that now?
你現在可以試試看嗎？
Just put it and say it together.
只要放上去然後一起說 母親，我是靈。再一次, 母親，我是靈。再一次, 母親，我是靈。再一次, 母親，我是靈。母親，我是靈
And a humbler way could be also: ëMother, am I the Spirit?í
還有一種更謙卑的方式可以是：「母親，我是靈嗎？」 「母親，我是靈嗎？」 「母親，我是靈嗎？」 ...
See now...
現在，你看...
Now, Sahasrara breaking took place
頂輪的開啟
on the 5th of May 1970.
發生在 1970 年 5 月 5 日
I was just pushed into it.
我只是順勢而為
Then I said one has to now break it.
於是我說現在必須打破它
And if you see a very thin line of Kundalini
而如果你看到一條非常細的像一條線般的昆達里尼
really breaks the Sahasrara through the heart chakra.
確實是透過心輪來突破頂輪
Here is the heart chakra.
這裡是心輪
Through the heart chakra point only it breaks. If your heart is not clean,
唯有通過心輪點才能突破。如果你的心不清淨
it will not break.
就無法穿透
So the first and the foremost thing
所以首要之務
is your Shiva Tattwa, is your heart.
就是你的濕婆本質，也就是你的心
Heart must be kept absolutely clean.
心必須保持絕對純淨
There should be nothing,
不應該有任何事物
that is doubting,
存有懷疑
that is confused,
或是困惑
that is angry,
那是憤怒的
that is ambitious,
那是野心勃勃的
that is afraid of;
那是恐懼的；
nothing of that kind should be in the heart.
心中不該存有這類情緒
Just be confident.
保持信心
Just leave it into the hands of God.
就把它交給神的手中
Because that is the point where the Kundalini breaks it
因為那是昆達里尼穿透的關鍵點
and if that point is heavy,
如果那個點很沉重
you can never break the Sahasrara.
你永遠無法打開頂輪
then it happens, itís such a vicious circle again sets in,
然後就這樣，一個惡性循環開始了
those people who have a bad heart, they come to me
那些心術不正的人，他們來找我
and they cannot get realisation. So they have an additional chance
而他們無法獲得自覺。所以他們又多了一次機會來攻擊
to attack me by saying ëWe never got the realisation,
他們攻擊我說：「我們從未得到自覺
we never felt the vibrations, so how is it, that You are this?í
也從未感受到生命能量，那你怎麼可能是這個？」
Because already your heart is dirty, you see.
因為他們的心早已污穢，明白嗎
It starts there emitting manifesting its spirit.
它從那裡開始散發並顯現其本性
And it goes and adding up and adding up
然後它不斷累積、不斷累積
and then they can build up a big story against me.
接著他們就能編造出一個對我不利的大故事
But the main thing is you have come to ask for something so great.
但最重要的是你們來此請求的是如此偉大的事物
You have to be, have a heart which is humble,
你們必須要有一顆謙卑的心
steadfast
堅定不移
and also proud of it self.
同時也以此自豪
Because in this heart is the Spirit which is going to be enshrined.
因為在這心中將供奉著靈
Now what do I do about your realisation.
現在我該如何對待你們的覺醒
My heart is very pure,
我的心非常純淨
absolute purity.
絕對的純淨
There is not even the slightest ripple
連一絲漣漪都沒有
of anything else but love for you.
除了對你的愛之外別無他物
Even if I get angry it is out of love.
即使我生氣也是出於愛
Even if I say something sometimes harshly, it is out of love,
即使我有時說話嚴厲，那也是出於愛
to keep you out of troubles.
為了讓你們遠離麻煩
But, in my heart there is nothing but pure love, pure love.
但在我心中，除了純粹的愛之外別無他物，純粹的愛
And this pure love is the pure Vidya, is the pure knowledge.
而這純粹的愛就是純粹的智慧，是純正的知識
Is the pure knowledge, is pure Vidya.
是純正的知識，是純粹的智慧
The complete technique of purity it knows.
它知曉純淨的完整技巧
How does the water purify you?
水是如何淨化你的？
Do you know the technique what the water does to you?
你知道水對你施展了什麼技巧嗎？
The complete technique of purity resides
純淨的完整技巧
in the heart
存在於心
and how do I give you realisation
而我該如何讓你自覺
is to put you in my heart.
是把你放在我的心裡
Bathe you there nicely.
好好地在那裡沐浴你
Have you seen crocodiles?
你看過鱷魚嗎？
Crocodiles have; are very ferocious;
鱷魚有；非常兇猛；
but when they hatch their eggs, they take all little, little crocodiles
但當牠們孵化蛋時，會把所有小小鱷魚寶寶
in their big mouth, you see,
含在牠們的大嘴裡，你看
and you should see the eyes of the crocodile, as is full of love
你該看看鱷魚的眼神，充滿了愛意
and all such...
還有這類...
as the children hatch.
當孩子們孵化時
And the crocodile then put the mouth inside the water
然後鱷魚把嘴伸進水裡
and cleanses them like this.
像這樣清洗牠們
First thing I do is to give you birth in my heart
我做的第一件事就是在心中孕育你們
and then cleanse you there in my heart,
然後在我的心中淨化你
and then take you
然後帶領你
through my Sahasrara. I give you your second birth.
經由我的頂輪。我賜予了你第二次誕生(重生)
Many people ask, that ëwhat happens to our karma and this?í
許多人問：「我們的業力會怎樣？」
I say: "I cleanse it!"
我說：「我淨化它！」
It has to be cleansed.
必須被淨化
So many people have asked one question so many times,
許多人反覆詢問同一個問題
that how is it that Kundalini is such a difficult thing and how is it,
為何坤達里尼是如此困難的事物，以及它..
You can do so well?
為什麼你可以運作的如此輕易？
I say, there must be something special about me.
我說，我一定有什麼特別之處
I need not tell them who I am.
我不需要告訴他們我是誰
If I say Adi Shakti, they say some sort of a (inaudible) woman,
如果我說太初之母，他們會說這是 ..
see who is about to Adi Shakti or else Shakti itself
看看誰是太初之母，或者就是力量本身
- power itself is horrifying and then on top of that is ëAdi Shaktií.
力量本身是令人畏懼的，更何況是太初之母的力量
But this is the Adi Shakti of love
但這是太初之母之愛
which is beyond human conception.
這超越了人類的理解
Only by its power you can recognise it and understand it.
唯有透過它的力量，你才能認出並理解它
How it cleanses you.
它如何淨化你
Thatís how people get cured. They donít know how they get cured.
這就是人們如何被治癒的。他們不知道自己是如何被治癒的
Just with a photograph under your pillow.
只需將一張照片放在你的枕頭下
There is another actress in India who is getting cured,
印度還有一位女演員正在痊癒
a very famous actress, with Sahaja Yoga.
一位非常著名的女演員，透過霎哈嘉瑜伽
Just they canít understand and they cannot explain.
只是他們無法理解也無法解釋
But this is a pure knowledge of cleansing
但這是一門淨化的純粹知識
which is built in that photograph, built in!
這張照片裡已內建了一切，已內建完成！
It knows vibrations.
它能感知生命能量
It knows everything. The whole technique is built inside.
它知曉一切。整個技巧都已內建其中
Once you have the vibrations, you donít have to learn
一旦獲得生命能量，就無須再學習
any technique, it works out by itself.
任何技巧，它都會自行運作
It is very subtle.
這是非常精微的
It is complete Brahma Shakti.
它是完整的梵天能量
It is a very powerful, very penetrating, very understanding;
它非常強大、極具穿透力且充滿理解力；
but it has all its knowledge built in itself.
它本身內裡已具備一切智慧
Itís the Shuddha Vidya, is the pure knowledge.
這就是純淨知識（Shuddha Vidya）
When you say Nirmala Vidya is also the same.
當你說無瑕知識（Nirmala Vidya）時也是一樣的
It is immaculate.
它是完美無瑕的
It cannot be compared with anything else.
這是無可比擬的
The technique is so perfect,
這技巧如此完美
that it never fails.
從不失誤
It knows all the permutations and combinations.
它通曉一切變化與組合
It knows how to work it out.
它懂得如何運作
One has to enter into the kingdom of God
人必須進入神的國度
to see the working of all these techniques.
才能見證所有這些技巧的運作
That is why it was necessary to open the Sahasrara of people.
這就是為何必須開啟人們的頂輪
Otherwise everything is Greek and Latin for people
否則對人們來說，這些都只是天書般難懂
who listen to all these great prophets
那些聆聽偉大先知的人們
and to great Avataras; they thought they were talking trough their hats.
以及偉大的降世神祇；他們以為這些人只是在胡言亂語
I mean that nowadays we talk through our hats only.
我是說現今我們才真的是在胡說八道
Because Sahasrara is there
因為頂輪就在那裡
and through Sahasrara we hear and we talk.
並且透過頂輪，我們可以聽懂與交談
To break the Sahasrara was very important.
開啟頂輪是極為重要的事
Of course you were also ready to receive it.
當然，你們也已準備好接收這份能量
The time had come. Mutual understanding was there
時機已然成熟。兩方相互理解
and it worked out.
並且順利運作
Itís a tremendous thing that has happened.
這是一個極其重大的事件
It should work out in England.
在英國也應該能夠順利運作
I should be here on this day
我在這天來到這裡
because as I have told you before, England is the heart,
因為正如我之前告訴過你們的，英國是宇宙的心臟
heart of the Universe.
宇宙的心臟
So we should see whatís wrong with us. Very important
所以我們應該檢視自己有什麼問題。這非常重要
for us to see as English people,
對我們這些英國人來說
living in England, whatís wrong with us, with our heart,
生活在英國，我們的心輪有什麼問題
because we are responsible for this great happening,
因為我們對這偉大的事件負有責任
because only through heart...
因為只有透過心...
[Tape one ends here. Second tape follow]
[第一捲錄音帶到此結束。第二捲接續]
...as political structure and as an individual.
...無論是政治結構還是個人層面
Because if the English
因為如果英國人
could clear the atmosphere of England,
能夠淨化英國的氛圍
it would be very easy to click the Sahaja Yoga throughout the world
要在全球各地推廣霎哈嘉瑜伽會變得非常容易
and that is why the responsibility of English is much more.
這就是為什麼英國人的責任更加重大
One good thing has started
有一件好事已經開始了
after my visit to Australia;
在我造訪澳洲之後；
people have started donating land to us.
人們已經開始捐贈土地給我們
Now we have got a plot of land in [unsure], Bombay,
現在我們在孟買[不確定]取得了一塊地
very near there about,
就在那附近
I think,
我想
about fifty miles away from Bombay.
距離孟買約五十英里
Weíve got another plot of land of seven acres
我們還有一塊七英畝的土地
which was donated to us.
是捐贈給我們的
There is also possibility of us getting a bigger land of twenty five acres,
我們也有可能獲得一塊更大的二十五英畝土地
which some of you have seen, along the River Neda.
你們有些人已經看過，沿著內達河的那塊地
And also there is a possibility
而且還有機會
of getting another nice land of seven acres in Pune.
在普納取得另一塊七英畝的好地
In Delhi they have offered us a very, very beautiful land
在德里，他們提供給我們一塊非常非常漂亮的土地
along a lake and a beautiful surroundings of a forest,
沿著湖畔，四周環繞著美麗的森林景緻
very much near the river Yamuna.
距離亞穆納河非常近
So now, my visit to Australia has materialised
如今，我對澳洲的訪問已成真
but my stay in England
但我在英國的停留
must materialise other thing is the cleansing.
必須具體化其他事物就是淨化
First of all let us all start from our individual,
首先讓我們所有人都從個人做起
our individual hearts
從我們個人的內心開始
and then try to expand it.
然後試著擴展它
Every time, what I find is this
每次，我所發現的都是這樣
that whatever you are supposed to do, you do just the opposite.
你應該要做的事情，偏偏都反其道而行
Like ëliverí,
就像肝臟
as I said is Europe
如同我所說的在歐洲
and liver drinks the most of it.
而肝臟喝最多的酒精
They produced the best wines;
他們釀造出最優質的葡萄酒
theyíre experts in the wines.
他們是葡萄酒的專家
The liver, liver produces the wines. You see this is the best part.
肝臟，在肝臟生產酒。你看這是最糟糕的部分
If you imagine,
如果你想像
if you imagine distillery in your liver, what will happen.
如果你想像你的肝臟是個酒廠，會發生什麼事
So the liver has become the distillery.
所以肝臟變成了酒廠
This is very surprising.
這非常令人訝異
Now, this is the heart - heart has to be large-harted,
現在，這是心——心必須是寬宏大量的
one has to be large-hearted.
一個人必須心胸寬廣
So you have become small-hearted.
所以你們變得心胸狹隘
A man with a heart is very courageous,
一個心輪敞開的人非常勇敢
very bold, very heard-bolding.
非常勇敢、非常振奮人心的
Here we have lots of fears,
我們這裡卻充滿了許多恐懼
problems and poets like Lord Byron.
問題和像拜倫勳爵這樣的愁苦詩人
Our idea of universality is so limited
我們對普世性的觀念是如此有限
that we think we live somewhere away from the rest of the world
我們以為自己生活在遠離世界其他地方之處
and we are just here and we should not be touched by anybody else.
而我們就在這裡，不該受到他人干擾
This is our heart, with the heart has to circulate all over the world
這是宇宙的心輪，這顆心必須流轉於全世界
and gather all the filth of the world and cleansed it.
收集世間一切污穢並加以淨化
You have gathered the filth, alright, but cleansing part...
你們已經積累了污穢，好吧，但淨化的部分...
Circulation they have done alright. They have been up to China,
他們已經完成了循環，沒錯。他們到過中國
they have been up to every place.
到過每個地方
I mean every, every nook and corner they have reached you see,
我是說每個，每個角落他們都到達了，你明白嗎
with their little heart.
用他們狹窄的小心靈
But when they have gathered all that with them, they donít know
但當他們把一切都收集起來時，卻不知道
how to cleanse it.
該如何淨化它
That they better do it,
他們最好這麼做
this is their job.
這是他們的工作
So this test you should put to all your problems here
所以這個考驗你應該用在所有你在這裡遇到的問題上
and youíll be amazed that the heart needs cleansing,
你會驚訝地發現心輪需要淨化
enlargement of the heart,
需要擴展心輪
greatness of the heart,
心輪的偉大
the health of the heart
心輪的健康
and the all-compassing forgiveness of the heart.
以及心輪的全面包容與寬恕
And ego is the worst enemy of heart,
而自我是心輪最糟糕的敵人
is the worst enemy. If anything gives you heart attack - it is your ego.
是最大的敵人。如果有什麼會讓你心臟病發作——那就是你的自我
And you have egos of various types.
而且英國人有各種各樣的自我
All kinds of egos can be found here.
在這裡可以找到各種各樣的自我
All kinds you see as you can find all kinds of wines in (inaudible).
就像在歐洲能找到各式各樣的酒一樣，在這裡你能看到各種各樣的自我
So we have to also know what kind of food
所以我們也必須了解
we require for this heart to be kept cleansed.
需要什麼樣的食物來保持這顆心輪的潔淨
First of all we must develop a heart
首先我們必須培養一顆
which has sweet feelings for others,
對他人懷有甜美感受的心
understanding for others,
理解他人
generosity for others.
對他人的慷慨
It is not reading the novel that you get there,
讀小說可不會讓你達到那裡
but
但
an understanding of a heart that loves,
一顆懂得愛的心
that cares for you.
那份對你的關懷
It may quarrel with someone,
或許會與人爭吵
may be jealous of someone, maybe that,
或許會妒忌他人，諸如此類
but should love from the heart.
但應該發自內心地去愛
You can never see that person being harmed by any chance.
你絕不願看到那個人受到任何傷害
All
全部
the wealth of the world, all the ego of the world
世間的財富、世間所有的自我
you will deny to give your love.
你會拒絕所有這些,就為了付出你的愛
The love giving capacity
愛的能力
has to be increased
必須提升
and nourished by things that talk about generosity [unclear].
並透過談論慷慨的事物來滋養
Like save the power business is useless.
像是節省這種事是沒有用的
Save the heart you should start now.
現在就該開始拯救心輪
You have to save the heart
你必須拯救心輪
because it is you the English who are going to save the heart
因為正是你們這些英國人要來拯救
of the universe.
整個宇宙的心輪
So the Sahaja Yogis have to have very large heartedness.
所以霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須心胸非常寬廣
Very clean heart.
非常純潔的心
There should be no cunningness.
不該有任何狡詐
No cunningness in the heart.
心中不可存有狡詐
While you know English have been the most cunning race
你知道英國人一向是世界上最狡猾的民族
all over the world. People know about. Oh!
全世界都知道。噢！
If there is an Englishmen - had it!
要是遇到英國人－那就完了！
Only somebody who can beat English is Indian.
唯一能打敗英國人的只有印度人
They know how to out beat you. There is a big competition.
他們知道如何擊敗你。這是一場激烈的競爭
I donít know which one wins.
我不知道哪個會贏
But if it comes to Indians, they can out beat it.
但如果說到印度人，他們可以超越這個
Now the latest is the guru system.
現在最新的產品是假導師系統
From here the English went
從這裡開始，英國人
and all the Western people went to raid all the developing countries.
以及所有西方人掠奪所有發展中國家
So the greatest of greatest, our India, has
因此，最偉大的，我們的印度，便
created such cunning people, absolutely cunningness,
造就了如此狡猾的人，絕對的狡詐
that they be fooled you very nicely.
他們把你們耍得很徹底
All the English went nicely be-fooled
所有英國人都被巧妙地耍得團團轉
and all the Americans
還有所有美國人
and all the Australians. All of them put together
以及所有澳洲人。他們全都被一網打盡了
could not find a few cunning people from India.
在印度找不到幾個狡猾的人
So I should say for the time being they have an upper hand.
所以我應該說目前他們佔了上風
Maybe
也許
the English today with their clean heart
今天這些英國人帶著純潔的心
develops such a sharp,
發展出如此鋒利的
such a sharp edge to their intelligence
如此鋒利的智慧鋒芒
that they can expose all these people
以至於他們能夠揭露所有這些人(假導師)
and cleanse
並予以淨化
the minds of the people who have been fogged
人們的心智已被蒙蔽
by the mesmerism of this cunning people.
被這些狡猾之人的催眠術所迷惑
So one has to realise
因此每個人必須體認到
that every action has a reaction,
每個行為都會帶來反作用力,
but the reaction comes the way
但反應的方式取決於
the reactor is.
反應者本身
Like the Indians are cunning but sly.
就像印度人狡猾但狡詐
English are cunning but intelligent.
英國人狡猾但聰明
So they do it in such an intelligent way you see,
所以你看他們做事的方式非常聰明
theyíll cut your throat and not even a single drop of blood will fall out.
他們會割斷你的喉嚨，卻連一滴血都不會流出來
They know all the laws and regulations, how to cut the throat of a person.
他們熟知所有法律規章，知道如何割斷一個人的喉嚨
But the Indians, they will not even cut your throat
但印度人，他們甚至不會割斷你的喉嚨
and you will become mad.
你會變得瘋狂
Just they know how to do it, they are even more dangerous
他們知道怎麼做，甚至更危險
and subtler.
且更加隱微
I mean, I donít know, they might have got first initiations from English
我是說，我不知道，他們可能已經從英國人那裡得到第一次啟示
and now they are teaching their gurus, like that I believe.
現在他們甚至在打擊自己的導師，我覺得很不可思議
The cunning they have learned, there is no end to it.
他們學到的狡猾伎倆，簡直永無止境
And for everything they have an argument and a suggestion,
對任何事情他們都能提出論點和建議
whatever it is.
無論那是什麼
You will be happy to know that one of them - Ravana
你們會很高興知道其中一個 - 羅波那(假導師)
has got a paralytic attack now
現在已經中風癱瘓了
and he has got a broken neck
而且他的頸椎斷裂
and he is lying in a hospital secretly.
正秘密地躺在醫院裡
So thatís one thing has already been done.
所以這是其中一件已經完成的事
Now, today is a day of very great celebration,
而今天是一個非常值得慶祝的日子
very great celebration,
非常值得慶祝的日子
because it celebrates the rebirth of the universe.
因為它慶祝宇宙的重生
It is nice to celebrate the great advent of great people
慶祝偉大人物的偉大降臨是件美好的事
and their birth dates and all that.
以及他們的誕生日等等
Like we celebrate Christmas,
就像我們慶祝聖誕節一樣
we celebrate the birth date of Nanaka and all these people
我們慶祝太初導師納納克和其他人的生日
- is great, no doubt.
- 這很棒，毫無疑問
But this is the greatest when
但這才是最偉大的時刻
every human being needs to be reborn,
當每個人都需要重生時
such a great thing.
如此非凡之事
It is a very great day and an event,
這是一個極為偉大的日子與事件
when all the humans being were promised to get their realisation.
當全人類都被允諾將獲得他們的自覺
Without that you would never have known the Spirit.
若無此，你們將永遠無從知曉靈
You would never have known God Almighty.
你永遠不會認識全能的上主
You would never have known the love
你永遠不會知曉那份愛
that is permeating all of you.
正滲透在你們每個人之中
We would never have felt that love, that power
我們永遠無法感受那份愛，那股力量
that controls the whole universe.
那掌控著整個宇宙的力量
You would have been blind and blind and blind.
你將會一而再、再而三地盲目下去
So this is one of the greatest days
因此這是最偉大的日子之一
that we have to celebrate with great joy and happiness
我們必須以無比的喜悅與快樂來慶祝
because it celebrates the emancipation,
因為它慶祝的是解放
the evolution and the rebirth of the humanity.
人類的進化與重生
Because the Advents and all these great
因為這些降世與所有偉大的
Incarnations do not need any rebirth.
降世神祇並不需要任何重生
They are permanently just the same, they are permanently chiefs.
他們永遠都是一樣的，永遠都是首領
Thereís no change in Them, nothing.
他們沒有任何改變，一點都沒有
So what is there to celebrate their birthday, I donít understand,
所以慶祝他們的生日有什麼意義呢？我不明白
every year they are just the same, their age is just the same,
每年他們都一樣，年齡也始終如一
they remain the same. What is a birthday, they never grow,
他們始終如一。什麼是生日，他們從未成長
they never mature, they over matured already.
他們從未成熟，他們早已過度成熟
But it is a great thing that you all should
但這是一件很棒的事，你們都應該
jump into that great realm of Divinity,
躍入那神聖的偉大境界
that you should know about the All-pervading power
你應該了解那無所不在的力量
and that you should become aware
並且你應該覺知到
of that flow of the power through you.
那股力量流經你
Without this everything is useless.
少了這個，一切都毫無意義
Everything is darkness.
一切皆為黑暗
Everything is confusion and relative.
一切皆是混亂與相對
So let us all really today celebrate
因此讓我們今天真正地慶祝
for all other Sahaja Yogis who have received realisation,
所有其他獲得自覺的霎哈嘉瑜伽行者
all over the world.
全世界都有
They are all putting their attention to you
他們全都將注意力放在你身上
and today
而今天
they are all doing their pujas in their own places.
他們都在各自的地方進行普祭
We have to think of them,
我們必須想著他們
because all of you are one,
因為你們都是一體的
connected with each other in love and in common bondage of your Mother.
在愛中與共同的母親連結中彼此相連
May God Bless you all!
願上帝保佑你們所有人！
Can I have some water?
我可以喝點水嗎？
As desired by you, we already got a video.
如你們所願，我們已經拿到澳洲錄影帶了
Video tape, did you get the video tape, did you get it?
錄影帶，你們拿到錄影帶了嗎，拿到了嗎？
From Hong Kong, imagine in Hong Kong the Chinese are great people.
來自香港，想像香港的中國人都是了不起的人
Chinese are tremendous.
中國人非常了不起
I mean they have our traditions,
我是說他們擁有我們的傳統
Indian traditions.
印度的傳統
I mean they are very traditional people.
我是說他們是非常傳統的民族
But they are
但他們是
westernised as far as other things are concerned.
在西方化的其他方面也是如此
I mean there is a big palace, Chinese have a big palace
我是說，中國人有座宏偉的宮殿
and they have not lost their aesthetics as Indians have lost.
而他們並未像印度人那樣喪失美感
You see, they have all your labour class aesthetics.
你看，他們具備所有勞動階層的審美觀
Indians have plastics and nylons, you see,
印度人有塑膠和尼龍，你看
but not Chinese.
但中國人沒有
Chinese have maintained their aesthetics.
中國人保持了他們的美學
I was surprised.
我感到驚訝
Any questions?
有任何問題嗎？
Bala, I am so sorry for the whole thing.
巴拉，整件事我感到非常抱歉
But we have done a good job, I must say.
但我必須說，我們做得很好
We have done a good job.
我們做得很好
I tell you because we had no communication with you here.
我告訴你們，因為我們在這裡與你們沒有任何聯繫
Phillip did not know any address, nothing.
菲利普不知道任何地址，什麼都不知道
I did not know how to contact those people in Ceylon
我不知道該如何聯繫錫蘭的那些人
and we had already planned out to go to Hong Kong.
而且我們已經計劃好要去香港了
All my plans as usual, were all upside down.
我所有的計劃，照例全都亂了套
You know this, it all works out this way.
你知道的，事情總是這樣發展
There was one lady called [unsure].
有位女士名叫[不確定]
She came from Hong Kong
她是從香港來的
and she wanted me to go to Hong Kong
她想讓我去香港
and just to give her lesson perhaps, you see, it worked out that way.
也許只是為了給她上一課，你看，事情就這樣發生了
So what to do?
那該怎麼辦？
They say there is no plane direct from Hong Kong
他們說沒有從香港直飛的班機
you have to come back to Singapore,
你得先回到新加坡
if you have to go to Australia.
如果你必須去澳洲的話
So this was a big problem. We thought that better do Hong Kong
這真是個大問題。我們想說不如先去香港
and come back and then to Australia.
然後再從那裡前往澳洲
Modi was there Rahulís wife was there,
莫迪在那裡，拉胡爾的妻子也在那裡
both of them went down.
他們兩個都下去了
India has done one good thing, we are getting donations of land.
印度做了一件好事，我們正在獲得土地捐贈
This is something great.
這真是太棒了
If we have no place we can at least pitch our tents there.
如果沒有地方，至少我們可以在那裡搭帳篷
What else...something?
還有什麼...其他事情嗎？
Yogi:  Can we do your Puja?
瑜伽士：我們可以做您的普祭嗎？
Can we take your puja?
我們能進行您的普祭嗎？
Puja, now, alright,
普迦儀式現在開始，好的
better have it.
最好準備好